briantracy.com 2018-12-28

# Privacy Policy | Brian Tracy

## Terms of Use, Privacy, and GDPR Compliance

The new General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) went into effect on 25th May 2018. Brian Tracy International is updating its privacy policy to provide you with increased transparency into the personal data it collects, how it is used, and the controls you have over your personal data. By using the Brian Tracy International website, and all affiliated Brian Tracy International pages, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

Brian Tracy International knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. The protection of your personal data, and compliance with GDPR is a very important concern. We therefore deal with your personal data in compliance with the applicable legal data protection provisions.

For information on specific aspects of our GDPR compliance, please click the appropriate link below.

  * Privacy Policy and Use of Website
  * Terms and Conditions
  * Data Protection
  * How we collect member, visitor or user information
  * Data Transfer
  * Request record of your data

If you have any questions or concerns, please contact your personal Asset Manager, or [the Brian Tracy International Data Protection Officer](mailto:rob@brandetize.com)

This Privacy Policy sets forth the policies and practices with respect to information or data that is received or gathered regarding members, visitors and users (collectively “you” and “your”). [www.briantracy.com](https://briantracy.com/) and all related sites of Brian Tracy International may be referred to collectively as “[www.briantracy.com](https://briantracy.com/)”, “Brian Tracy International”, “us”, “we”, “Site”, “Website” or “the Company”

CAREFULLY READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY BECAUSE BY YOUR USE OF THIS SITE AND ITS SERVICES YOU WILL BE EXPRESSLY SIGNIFYING THAT YOU AGREE TO THIS POLICY AND THAT YOU ASSENT TO THE TERMS OF THIS AGREEMENT, INCLUDING THE USE OF ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION THAT YOU SUPPLY OR THAT IS COLLECTED ABOUT YOU AS DETAILED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT EXPRESSLY AGREE WITH ALL OF THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY YOU SHOULD NOT USE THIS SITE OR ITS SERVICES.

## Terms and Conditions

### Copyright and Trademark Rights

The texts, images, graphics and the layout of this website displayed on this website are subject to copyright. Violations of this will be prosecuted both under civil and criminal law. Reproduction of all or part of this website is only permitted with the prior written consent of Brian Tracy International. The individual use does not authorize the transfer of content to third parties. Trademarks used on this website are protected and all rights are owned by the respective trademark owners.

## Data Protection

For us, Brian Tracy International, the protection of your personal data is a very important concern. It is therefore natural for us to deal with your personal data in compliance with the applicable legal data protection provisions.

With this privacy policy we explain to you which data in the context of the use of this website are collected, processed and used for which purposes and which rights you are entitled to.

### Data Collection and Processing When Visiting Our Website

As is usual with many websites, the retrieval of the individual web pages from our web servers and the web analytics software Google Analytics we use automatically collects and processes the following non-personal data: 

### Collection and Processing of Personal Data and Consent

We collect, process and use personal data such as your name, postal address, email address or other contact details **only if they have been entered by you on the website and transmitted to us** and to the extent that such collection, processing and use is permitted by law or covered by your consent.

The use of certain services of our website such as, information and study requirements, the contact form, the callback service and the registration for our newsletter makes the collection, processing and use of personal data necessary. In this case, we take the requirement of data economy seriously and only collect those personal data marked as mandatory in the respective online forms that are required for the purpose of using and processing the respective service. The personal data provided in the other form fields are voluntary and used by us for the purpose of being able to address you more personally and / or individually or to increase the service for you, for example through the possibility of queries. For each of these services, we point out to you, at the appropriate place on our website, the purposes for which we collect, process and use the respective personal data. Any collection, processing and use of your personal data will only be for the stated purposes and to the extent necessary to achieve these purposes.

In addition, if your prior consent is required for certain data collection, processing and use, such as service telephone calls and the use of our newsletter or our information e-mails, we will, of course, ask you for your consent beforehand at the corresponding section of our website ask. These declarations of consent are recorded by us and can be accessed by you at any time at the appropriate place on our website. We recommend that you print out the declarations of consent for your own documents. **You are entitled to revoke your given consent at any time in whole or in part with effect for the future.** Even such a revocation will be logged by us.

When necessary/requested, your data will be destroyed in compliance with all GDPR rules and requirements.

## How We Collect Member, Visitor or User Information

The information we gather falls into two categories:

  1. Information collected as a result of you navigating through the Site.
  2. Personal information you voluntarily supply when you subscribe, order, post a message, photo, video or sound recording, send a message to another user, or participate in a chat room, complete a survey, enter a contest, or apply for a promotional product.

The first type of information we collect can be thought of as "passive" information in that we collect certain details about your visit to our site without you actively inputting any identifying information. This type of passive information that we collect and store in our databases, may include one or more of the following types of information ("Data"): your Internet Protocol (IP) address; the name of the domain name from which you access the Internet; the IP address of the Website from which you linked to the Site or our network of sites; browser data; email address data; and the date and time you access our Site and its functions. For example, when a visitor, member, subscriber, or other Site user requests web pages from the Site’s server, clicks on banners or other links or otherwise uses or views the Site’s services, products or other functions, we or our agents may automatically collect some information ("Data") about the visitor, member, subscriber or user. This information may include the IP address from which the Site is being accessed, the pages or links that were requested, the special preferences or requests of the user and cookie information received from the computer of the visitor, member, subscriber or user. While the collection of Data described above could be thought of as passive, the second way we collect information is more active.

For example, we may ask you to provide personal information. Whether or not you provide this personal information is completely optional. This "Optional Information" may include your name, username, e-mail address, physical address (or part of it such as your zip code), telephone number, gender, marital status, occupation, education and any special interests or affiliations. Additional "Optional Information," such as a credit card number, expiration date, security code and billing address may be requested for participation in special promotions or offers, or for billing and shipping information. We may also use "Optional Information" to verify identity, and protect against fraud. When a subscriber, member or user of this Site sends any personal communication or correspondence, by any means, to the Site, another Site User, the Company or any employees, agents or representatives of Company or Site, we may collect and use any and all such information and all other Data regarding that communication including the I.P. address the communication originated from. Once you submit personal information to the Company or Site we may collect and store information about your activities on the Site. 

### Cookies

Cookies are one of the tools that we use to passively collect Data. 

Internet cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and to provide personalized features and marketing. Cookies are used for authenticating, tracking and maintaining specific information about users, such as site preferences or shopping cart contents. Most Internet browsers allow the option to enable or disable cookies. You may disable cookies, but this may make portions of this Site unusable. Cookies are simple pieces of data unable to perform any operation by themselves. They are neither spyware nor viruses, despite the detection of cookies from certain sites by many anti-spyware products. This Site uses cookies to make the browsing experience of our members, subscribers and users more efficient and convenient. Our system will use cookies to remember your web preferences, and to assist us in tracking and targeting the interests, preferences and desires of our Site users to present the most appropriate messages, offers and other communications to our users, and to generally enhance their experience at our Site. Any and all information about Site visitors, members, subscribers or users collected by the Company, the Site or any agents or affiliates of Company or Site, through the use of cookies or other similar means may be included in our database and used in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

We use remarketing pixels from sites including, but not limited to, Google, Facebook, and Twitter to aid in customized, targeted follow-up advertising. These third-party vendors show our ads on sites across the Internet by using cookies based on past visits to our website. Anyone can opt-out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting Google’s Ads Settings (<https://www.google.com/settings/ads>). Anyone can opt-out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page (<https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>). 

### You May Encounter Third Parties on Our Site

We want to inform you that third parties such as affiliates and advertisers use cookies on or in association with our Site. We often have no access or control over these cookies. We may also allow third party service providers to deliver special offers or services to Site users. We urge you to consult the privacy policies of any third party that you encounter on this Site. 

### Clear Gifs ("web Beacons")

Clear GIFs, also known as "web beacons" or "single-pixel GIF’s" are very small images (typically 1 x 1 pixel) that help websites understand their customers better. While any type of file can operate as a web beacon, clear GIFs are most popular because their very small file size prevents them from interfering in the websites’ operation. Clear GIFs function like cookies, in that they are used to track and measure online actions taken by website users. In contrast to cookies clear GIFs are not stored on a user’s hard drive, but are embedded into the graphics, text or other components of web pages. Web pages and graphical emails use codes that tell your computer what to do when a page is opened. While they typically contain text and graphics that you see on the screen, often web pages also contain instructions or tags' that then ask the website's server to send you further content (such as an image or a block of text that changes frequently). Web beacons are retrieved in the same way as the text and graphics that you see on a website or in an email, and the action of calling the material from another server allows the event to be counted. When a user's browser requests information from our Site we may use GIFs to gather "passive" information such as the IP address of your computer; the time the material was viewed; the type of browser that retrieved the image; and the prior existence of cookies from our Site. This is information that could be gathered through the use of cookies. Web beacons do not give any "extra" information away. They are simply a convenient way for us to gather the simple statistics and manage cookies. Clear GIFs may be used by third parties to monitor activity on the Site. Turning off the browser's cookies will prevent web beacons from tracking your specific activity, but web beacons may still record an anonymous visit from your IP address. 

## Facebook

Facebook Tools are used on the website and may use cookies, web beacons, and other storage technologies to collect or receive information from your websites and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target adds. You can opt out of the collection and find more information on your choices here: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> and [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). 

## Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies”, text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if IP anonymisation is activated on this website, your IP address will be shortened by Google beforehand within member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. 

Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage to the website operator. The IP address provided by Google Analytics as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. 

You can prevent the storage of cookies by a corresponding setting of your browser software; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest extent possible. In addition, you may prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading the browser plug-in available under the following link and install (<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>). 

Like many other websites, this website also uses the Google AdWords online advertising program and, as part of that, Google Conversion Tracking to measure which websites our ads work best on. Google AdWords sets a cookie on your computer if you’ve reached this website through a Google ad. These cookies lose their validity after 540 days and are not used for personal identification. If you visit certain pages of this website and the cookie has not yet expired, Google and we may recognize that you clicked on the ad and were redirected to this page. Each advertiser receives different cookies. Cookies can not be tracked through the websites of advertisers. The information obtained by using the conversion cookie is used to determine which visitors have triggered a specific action on our site through advertisements. We learn the total number of users who clicked on our ads, and which clicks resulted in an action. However, we do not receive any information that personally identifies a user. If you do not wish to participate in the tracking process, you can clear or disable the Google Conversion Tracking cookie from your Internet browser under User Preferences by setting your browser to block cookies from the domain “googleadservices.com”. You will not be included in the conversion tracking statistics. 

By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the context of Google Remarketing and Google Conversion Tracking in the manner and for the purposes set out above. Please refer to Google’s Privacy Policy before using this website if necessary. 

## Data Transfer

The personal data collected as part of the use of this website will not be disclosed to third parties or transmitted in any other way. Exceptions to this are transfers of personal data to our data processors, government institutions and authorities, as well as private rightholders on the basis of legal regulations or judicial or regulatory decisions and the transfer to state institutions and authorities in the event of attacks on our legal interests for legal or criminal prosecution purposes. External service providers that we use to operate the website or to perform certain services on our website, process personal data exclusively on our behalf and are contractually obliged to comply with the applicable statutory provisions on data protection and data security. They are not considered third parties in terms of data protection law. 

## How We Protect Your Information

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and to ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online. We shall continue to take reasonable steps to provide effective data protection at all times, however, no security technology can provide invulnerability to information compromise. Therefore Brian Tracy International cannot, and does not, guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to us or to any third party affiliated with the Site. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. 

## Your rights

### Information and Information Rights

At any time you have the right to information about the data stored about you, their origin and recipient as well as the purpose of the storage. You can contact us at the following address: support@briantracy.com or at the postal address 2840 Fifth Ave., Suite 400, San Diego, CA 92103. If you have any questions about our privacy policy or if you wish to receive more detailed information, you can also contact us at these addresses. 

We reveal only the last five digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. 

## Choice/Opt Out

If you are a newsletter subscriber, you always have the option of no longer receiving them. At the bottom of each newsletter there is an opt-out option. Simply click on “Please click here to unsubscribe”. 

## Correct/Update

Our customers can correct, access and update pertinent Personally Identifiable Information obtained through the site. Mechanisms include online, email, telephone, postal mail etc. This helps to assure that the information we collect is accurate and up to date. You can correct, access, and update your personal information by emailing the address [here](mailto:support@briantracy.com). 

## Request Record of your Stored Data

To request a report on what data has been stored related to your account, or to request that we delete all associated data, please email us [here](mailto:support@briantracy.com). 

## Conditions of Use, Notices and Revisions

If you choose to visit Brian Tracy International, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Notice and our Conditions of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of the law of the Luxembourg. Our business changes constantly. This Notice and the Conditions of Use will change also, and use of information that we gather now is subject to the Privacy Notice in effect at the time of use. 

## Change of Privacy Policy

From time to time, it may be necessary to change this privacy policy, for example as a result of the further development of our website or legal changes. Brian Tracy International therefore reserves the right to change the privacy policy at any time with effect for the future. Subscribers will be notified of any and all updates at the time they take place.

**Brian Tracy International**  
Phone: 1-858-436-7300  
Fax: 1-858-436-7301  
Email: [support@briantracy.com](mailto:support@briantracy.com)  
2840 Fifth Ave., Suite 400, San Diego, CA 92103  
Website: www.briantracy.com
